# **KATHRYN DIPIPPO**

60 Pembroke St, Newton, MA 02458 PHONE: (609) 751-7774

EMAIL: <a href="mailto:dipippo.k@gmail.com">dipippo.k@gmail.com</a> https://www.kathryndipippo.com/

## **SUMMARY**

Software developer specializing in full-stack development with a passion for efficient data structures and front-end design and implementation. Experienced in object-oriented programming and agile methodologies. Enthusiastic, dependable team player with strong project management and communication skills.

### **SKILLS**

Languages: Java, Python, Python, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, PHP, XML, C++

**Technologies/Frameworks:** Git, Atlassian, Slack, Postman, Bootstrap, jQuery, Materialize, Sketch, Photoshop

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Web and Mobile Applications Developer: Unbound Commerce - Newton, MA

June 2017 - Present

- Develop and maintain mobile e-commerce sites, most notably for Ashley Furniture and Restaurant Equippers
- Develop Android applications for e-commerce clients utilizing both native checkout
- Implementing and desktop site checkout proxying, most notably for Hudson Technologies

Consultant Intern: Tallan - Boston, MA

May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and implemented application customization feature in Virtual Tour internal program used by various clients, including the Massachusetts Legislature and Delaware Legislature
- Assisted in refactoring the video SQL database at the Massachusetts State House

Computer Science 1 Mentor: Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute - Troy, NY

August 2015 - May 2017

Assisted Computer Science 1 students during lab & office hour periods for four semesters

REU Intern: MIRTHE Center - Princeton, MA

Summer 2014 and 2015

- Participated on a research team to develop a device that measures a user's blood glucose levels using mid-infrared lasers
- 2014: implemented a MatLab GUI to be used by research students for further system testing
- 2015: refactored the GUI in Python to be used by patients at diabetic facilities for clinical trials
- Both experiences concluded with presenting a project abstract and poster at a week-long MIRTHE workshop

#### **PROJECTS**

Adoptapedia: HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, JavaScript - http://adoptapedia.com/

February 2013 - Present

- Created a website that serves as a widely used online resource for character designers and artists
- Developed cronjobs to update the group directory listing page daily

**Sushi Dogs:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript - <a href="http://www.kathryndipippo.com/SushiDogs/">http://www.kathryndipippo.com/SushiDogs/</a>

April 2017 - March 2018

- Designed and implemented tools for a niche character trading community, aimed at creating an easy-to-modify site with no programming experience needed
- Worked within the boundaries of maintaining complex databases without server-side capabilities through the use of a GitHub-hosted server and Google Spreadsheets

#### **EDUCATION**

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Aug 2013 - May 2017

B.S. Computer Science, Minor in Studio Arts